A Guide to the J. T. Shropshire papers, 1955-2005
Library of Virginia
- Series IX: Publications, 1962, 1970-1994, 2003-2005., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 14-15)
  Publications, 1962, 1970-1994, 2003-2005, consists of journal, magazine, and newspaper articles published regarding J. T. Shropshire's career as Senate clerk and as the governor's chief of staff; the governorships of Charles Robb, Gerald Baliles, and Doug Wilder; Wilder's political aspirations; the Wilder-Robb feud; Robb's scandals; the Virginia general assembly; and Virginia politics in general. Also includes annual reports of businesses, a U.S. Congressional report on Virginia Representative Dan Daniels, publications about the William and Mary MBA program, and an issue of the Martinsville Bulletin celebrating Martinville's and Henry County's bicentennial. Also contains newsletters of political, educational, and business organizations.
  - Articles, 1976, 1978, 1980. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Articles, 1981-1982 (excluding November 1981). (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Articles, November 1981. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1983. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Articles, 1984-1985. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Articles, 1986, 1988. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Articles, 1989. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Articles, 1991. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Articles, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Articles, 1994, 2003. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Articles, undated. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Hunter Andrews. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Doug Wilder: Virginia's Next Governor? by Ann Cheney 1988. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Playboy Interview: L. Douglas Wilder--Playboy (excerpted), 1991. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Doug Plays Hard--Regardie's (excerpted), June 1990. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - The First Black Governor--the Philadelphia Inquirer Magazine, page 30, 5 November 1989. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - The Resurrection of Chuck Robb--Regardie's page 70, October 1990. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - The Tale of the Tape--Regardie's, page 34, December 1990/January 1991. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Ghosts in the Governor's House--Richmond, page 36, November 1993. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Jay Shropshire: the Hustling Clerk of the Senate--Richmond Lifestyle, page 70, January 1980. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Where Has all the Laughter Gone?--Richmond Lifestyle, page 38, October 1981. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Standing by Their Man--Style Weekly, page 14, 15 October 1991. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Who Pulls the Strings?--Virginia Business, page 22, November 1989. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Feeding Frenzy--Virginia Business, page 16, September 1991. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Who's Running the Store While Wilder Runs for President?--Virginia Business page 14, January 1992. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Legislative agenda--Virginia Police Journal, page 25, Spring 1989. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Five Great Virginians I Have Known: Contemporary Leaders of the Commonwealth--Virginia Review page 20, May/June 1990. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - One Man Show--Washington Post Magazine, page 12, 9 June 1991. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - J. T. Shropshire obituary--William and Mary Alumni Magazine, page 123, Winter 2004/2005. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Annual report of B. F. Goodrich Company, 1962. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Annual report of Virginia Electric and Power Company, 1962. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Record--inaugural commemorative edition, 1970. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Capitol Comics, 1983. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Investigation of Travel on Corporate Aircraft Taken by Representative Dan Daniel: Report of the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct House of Representatives, 5 February 1986. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - The Executive MBA Program: the College of William and Mary Graduate School of Business. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report of the School of Business Administration, College of William and Mary, 1989. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Martinsville and Henry County 1791-1991 Bicentennial: a Pictoral History--Martinsville Bulletin, 27 October 1991. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Capitol Action: Publication of the House Clerk's Office, April-May 1986. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Legislative Administrator, January 1984, Winter 1990. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - The Pott Roast (honoring A. L. Philpott), 14 September 1987. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Quarterly Report--William and Mary MBA Alumni Association, June 1989. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - State Librarian's Update, October 1988. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - VRMA Kaleidoscope--Virginia Retail Merchants Association, February 1981. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Alabama's Legislative Process and Legislative Glossery. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Virginia Legislative Directory, 1991. (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Series X: General papers, 1982-1997, undated., Extent: 1 box. (Box 16)
  General papers, 1982-1997 and undated, contains ballots, bumper stickers, judicial records, newsletters, plans, phonograph records, photographs, postcards, programs, speeches, and other papers relating to politics, business, and other subjects.
  - Speeches and talks (John F. Kennedy album of speeches, Vernon Jordan, Doug Wilder, Mother Theresa), 1982, 1986, undated. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Programs and postcards, 1983-1991. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Legal papers and court cases, 1984-1997. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Henry County, Martinsville, and Ridgeway pamphlets and programs, 1987-1990. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Nauticus, 1989. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Bumper stickers. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Ballots. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Series XI: Videocassettes, campaign buttons, and ephemera., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 17-18)
  Videocassettes, campaign buttons, and ephemera contain video tapes of shows with J. T. Shropshire regarding Memorial Day, the state capital, and politics; campaign buttons for elections in Virginia and the United States; Elihu Root medal for the National Civilian Rifle Team; stickers of the Virginia state seal; business cards and name tag; and office plate.
  - Videocassettes of shows hosted by J. T. Shropshire regarding Memorial Day, the Capital, and politics. (Box 17)
  - Campaign buttons, medal, business cards, name tags, stickers, and door plate. (Box 18)
- Oversized materials, 1972-1991, undated., Extent: 1 box. (Box 19)
  Items in this box have holdings cards located within their proper series.
  - The First Black Governor--the Philadelphia Inquirer Magazine, page 30 (Series IX: Publications, box 14, folder 27), 5 November 1989. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Senate Clerk license plate (Series I: Clerk of the Senate, box 4, folder 23). (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Photographs--General Assembly, inauguration of Lieutenant Governor Richard J. Davis, portrait of Peter K. Babalas (Series VIII: Photographs, box 14, folder 4, folder 11), 1972, 1982, undated. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - John Fitzgerald Kennedy speeches (Series X: General Papers, box 16, folder 1). (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Standing by Their Man--Style Weekly, page 14 (Series IX: Publications, box 15, folder 4), 15 October 1991. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Commemorate the Two Hundredth Anniversary of the Independence of the United STates of America, from the Senators of the French Republic to the Senators of the United States--copy to Governor Mills Godwin of Virginia (Series I: Clerk of the Senate, box 1, folder 1), 24 January 1977. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Martinsville and Henry County 1791-1991 Bicentennial: a Pictoral History--Martinsville Bulletin (Series IX: Publications, box 15, folder 19), 27 October 1991. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Doug Wilder: lieutenant governor poster (Series V: Politics, box 10, folder 1), 1985. (Box 19, Folder 8)